# **Tobias Pristupin**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER St. Louis, MO

**1** +1 954-371-7815

p.tobias@wustl.edu | 😭 www.pristu.dev

## Summary\_

Hi, I'm Tobias. I am a self taught programmer from Argentina with 6 years of experience. I have experience in mobile development, compiler design, full stack web development, embedded systems, and competitive programming. More information about my projects can be found on my website.

## Education

### Washington University in St. Louis - Expected Graduation May 2023

St. Louis, MO

COMPUTER SCIENCE + MATHEMATICS MAJOR

Aug. 2020 - Present

 Attending on a full scholarship as an Ervin Scholar. GPA 3.97/4. Relevant coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms (A+), Discrete Mathematics (A+ and now working as a Teacher Assistant), Linear Algebra (A+), Full Stack Web Development CSE 330 (A+).

## **Cypress Bay High School**

Weston, FL

High School Apr. 2017 - Jul. 2020

 GPA: 5.1, standardized test scores in the 99th percentile. Recipient of the AP Scholar with Distinction Award and the National Hispanic Recognition Award. President of the Computer Science Club

## **Work Experience & Projects**

**Facebook** Menlo Park, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021

• Incoming SWE Summer intern for Mobile Code Mechanics Team

## **Lox Programming Language Research Study**

Washington University in St.

Louis 2020-21

RESEARCHER & DEVELOPER

• Developed an interpreter from scratch in C++ for the Lox Programming language as a personal project.

- Created a bytecode compiler and a stack based virtual machine for Lox, also in C++, as part of an independent research project under the supervision of Professor J. Shidal.
- Analyzed multiple research papers on Garbage Collection and implemented my own garbage collection algorithms for my compiler. Benchmarked the algorithms and wrote a research paper summarizing my findings.

**Smart RC Car** GitHub

**DEVELOPER - PERSONAL PROJECT** 

• Retrofitted old RC car with a Raspberry Pi to control acceleration and steering. RPI acts as a web server that can be controlled via wifi through a phone app.

**Minimal Running** GitHub

**DEVELOPER - PERSONAL PROJECT** 

2018-19

 Published Android application with 100+ downloads. Allows user to log their running activities and view statistics on their progress. Users can use an account to store their data online.

# **Volunteering**

#### **sErvin**

Washington University in St.

CO-PRESIDENT

Jan. 2019 - Present

- Restarted a community service group within John B. Ervin scholars that had been inactive for 5 years.
- Directed community outreach events with UnhousedSTL for a group of 30 scholars

#### Skills

#### **Experience with**

C++, Java, Python, JS, PHP, HTML/CSS, SQL, MongoDB, Node.js, React, Flask, Apache, Linux, Android Dev, Flutter, Arduino, Mathematica, Bilingual (Spanish and English)

JUNE 5, 2021 TOBIAS PRISTUPIN · RÉSUMÉ